btopenworld.com 2017-06-29

# BT.com | Privacy Policy

### Here you'll find lots of detail on how we collect and use your personal information.

On this site, "we", "our" and "BT" each mean all the companies that make up the BT Group. We collect information about you when you buy or use our Telephone, Broadband or TV services, or from other organisations such as credit agencies or other Telcos handling your calls. We may share this information between us so we can provide the services you order and manage your account.

By using any of our services or visiting our websites you agree to our use of your personal information as set out here.

### If you want to find out more about how we collect and use your personal information in different situations please click on the buttons above.

Back to top

When you order a phone service from us, we ask for your name, address, contact number, including mobile, and email address. We also ask for details on how you want to pay. That's so we can provide you with the service, charge you for it and let you know if we make changes to it. We also use your personal information to check your identity if you get in touch with us.

When you first order a phone service from us, or buy certain new services, we run a credit check on you. To do that we give some of your personal information to credit reference agencies.  
Read more about our credit checking processes.

When you sign up, we'll ask if you want your details in the Phone Book and other directories – like those online. If you agree, we'll publish your details and share your information with other communications providers who provide directory services. Ex-directory numbers are not included.

Unless you tell us not to, we will, from time to time, contact you to tell you about products or services we think you might be interested in. We might do this through the post, online, using push notifications via apps, via a text message, or on the phone. When we send you text messages, we also receive information from your mobile phone carrier such as your device ID (also known as IMEI).

When you use your phone we keep a record – including the number you call, the time and the length of the call so we charge you the right amount on your bill. Unless you tell us not to we may also use this information to tell you about products and services we think may be of interest to you.  
Read more about your choices on marketing.

If you take the Call Protect product from us, we will collect and retain details of all the telephone numbers which have called you. The last 20 numbers which have called you will also be displayed on your Call Protect Portal. We will use Your Blacklist and the BT Blacklist to stop you receiving unwanted or nuisance calls. We may add telephone numbers from Your Blacklist to the BT Blacklist. We will automatically redirect numbers on either Blacklist to your voicemail inbox. You should regularly check your voicemail inbox to ensure that the right calls are being redirected.

If we think there's been crime, fraud, misuse of, or damage to, our network, we'll use this information for our internal investigations and any subsequent prosecution(s).

Back to top

 **Save up to 25% on  
BT6500 Nuisance Call  
Blocker phones**

When you order TV products or services from us, we ask for your name, address, your preferred contact number, including your mobile and email address. We also ask for details on how you want to pay, such as your direct debit or credit card details, and information about your devices and viewing cards so we can provide you with the service.

Other information we may collect about your use of our TV services include details of the devices you use, the channels, programmes and adverts you watch on them, the services you access, how long you watch and what actions you take when doing so, such as how you view, record or fast forward programmes. We keep a record of the content that you buy and download.

We also record the IP addresses and MAC addresses of devices you view from and your user IDs and device passwords and pin codes for parental controls.

We need this information to be able to provide you with services which you have asked for on the devices you want to view our programmes and content on. This data also helps us to improve our services and the programmes we buy and make for your viewing pleasure.

We use your data to provide you with personalised services such as viewing recommendations. You can manage your choices regarding what you see when viewing content on our Apps by visiting the App store you have downloaded from.

If you opt out of personal recommendations on Apps, you may still get general content recommendations and adverts.

Where you take our TV services through our partners we share your information to help provide you with the service – and sometimes for marketing, but only if you've told us that's okay.  
Read more about your choices on marketing.

Back to top

 **BT Sport is FREE with BT  
Broadband or BT Infinity**

When you order broadband from us, or sign up to use BT Wi-fi, we ask for your name, address, contact number, including mobile, and email address. We also ask for details on how you want to pay. We might also need your direct debit or credit card details to charge you for the service. When we send you text messages, we also receive information from your mobile phone carrier such as your device ID (also known as IMEI).

We'll use your contact details to tell you about changes to our service; for example if we upgrade your line, or when there's a new technology (like fibre optic) in your neighbourhood.

Unless you tell us not to, we may use this data, from time to time, to contact you to tell you about products or services we think you might be interested in. We might do this through the post, online, using push notifications via apps, or on the phone.  
Read more about your choices on marketing.

Where you use our wi-fi partners' services, we share your information to help provide you with the service – and sometimes for marketing (but only if you've told us that's okay.)

We keep information about how you're using your broadband to help us understand and manage traffic flows on our network, improve our services and tell you about products you might be interested in. That includes IP addresses and other traffic data including websites you've visited. We may also use this information to provide you with certain services you ask us for – like parental controls on web access.

We are sometimes contacted by third parties who monitor illegal online file sharing on behalf of copyright holders. If we receive a claim that there has been illegal sharing on your broadband service, we may use your IP address to notify you. But unless we are required to by law, we will not disclose your personal information to the copyright holder or any party acting on their behalf.

The law says we have to keep certain information about how you use our internet services for 12 months. This information may be used by law enforcement agencies to prevent and detect crime and to protect national security. (But we only disclose information to them when we have been lawfully requested to do so.) If we think there's been crime, fraud, misuse of, or damage to, our network, we'll use this information for our internal investigations and any subsequent prosecution(s). We will also provide it in reply to other lawful requests for information such as about illegal online file sharing.

When you first log on to use your internet access service from BT you will be shown a screen asking if you want to activate parental controls or not. We keep a record of whether or not you have activated parental controls and will continue to offer them to you each time you log in if you ignore the request. The only data we will capture is whether or not you have activated parental controls and the level of filtering you have selected. We give numbers of activations to the Government and keep an aggregated and anonymous report of the sites which are blocked. We also record high level user behaviour, such as the number of times there has been an error in how the controls have worked, but we will not record the sites blocked against you.  
We give numbers of activations to the Government and keep an aggregated and anonymous report of the sites which are blocked. We also record high level user behaviour, such as the number of times there has been an error using the controls, but we will not record the sites blocked against you.  
For more information please refer to our Broadband [terms and conditions](https://www.productsandservices.bt.com/products/static/terms/) which cover parental controls.

We may also take steps in our network to protect you from threats from malicious domains which may attempt to infect your machine with malware associated with criminal threats. For more information please refer to our Broadband [terms and conditions](https://www.productsandservices.bt.com/products/static/terms/).

Back to top

 **Keep your family safe  
online with BT Family  
Protection**

When you order a mobile phone service from us, we ask for your name, title, address, date of birth and gender. We also ask for contact details including a phone number, email address and your current mobile number if you want to keep it. If you've already got a phone service with us, we ask for your BT ID number or account number too.

As well as that we ask for details on how you want to pay, like your bank details or credit card number. (So we can charge you for the service.)

If you're new to BT when you first order a mobile service from us, we run a credit check on you. To do that we give some of your personal information to credit reference agencies. Read more about our credit checking processes.

We also use your personal information to check your identity if you get in touch with us.

Unless you tell us not to, we'll also use this information to tell you about products and services we think you might be interested in. We might do that by post, online, using push notifications via apps, or on the phone. Read more about your choices on marketing.

If you come to us through a third party site, like uSwitch, we might need to match your order to the information they give us if we need to pay them.

When you use your mobile, we record certain things about that use. They include the amount you spend, the numbers you call or text (but not the content of the text), the numbers that call or text you, and the location of the cell that you make a call from (but that's kept anonymous). We also record the time and the length of all incoming and outgoing services like calls, texts and picture messages (MMS) while you're in the UK and abroad.

When you download a BT app from BT.com, we will record information about your device, such as its manufacturer. Where relevant, we will detail the additional data that we will receive through that BT app before you download it.  
We also look at which BT apps you use, your IP address and the websites you visit, so that we can tailor your online experience. Read more about browsing history here.

We record how much data you use, any extra spending outside of your plan and what you spend in your apps. That's so we can charge you the right amount on your bill, tell you if you're getting close to your usage limit, fix faults, and send you other messages about your service.

We keep information about the mobile phone or tablet you use with the BT Mobile service, including the device ID (or IMEI), the features on it (like whether it uses 3G or 4G), the type and model, and the operating system. This helps us understand how you're using BT Mobile and improve the overall service we give you.

Unless you tell us not to, we'll use your personal information to tell you about products and services we think you might be interested in. We might do that by post, online, using push notifications via apps, text message, or on the phone.  
Read more about your choices on marketing.

We don't share your personal information, except with the third parties we work with to deliver your mobile (and related) services. We might occasionally share information more widely to profile basic demographic data but it'll be anonymous and brought together with other customers' data.

We sometimes gather and pass on information about customers' interests, preferences and lifestyle, which we can work out from their interactions with us or get from third parties. But we always keep this data totally anonymous.

If we think there's been crime, fraud, misuse of, or damage to, our network, we'll use this information for our internal investigations and any prosecution(s) that might follow. We might also need to use it for managing traffic on the network, for emergency services or tracing malicious or nuisance calls.

The law says we have to keep certain information about how you use our services for 12 months, even if you stop using BT Mobile. Law enforcement agencies could use this information to detect crime and protect national security. We only ever disclose information to them when we receive a lawful request to do so.

### Children and Mobiles

BT recognises that many of today's children have grown up with the internet and are very familiar with how it works – often more so than their parents. This represents a challenge for parents, as it allows them to access inappropriate websites without suitable supervision, particularly if they have their own device, such as a Mobile. BT is therefore committed to helping parents protect children from such content through its Parental Controls feature. Further information can be on our website in the '[Stay safe with BT Parental Controls](http://home.bt.com/techgadgets/internet/stay-safe-with-bt-parental-controls-11363887238413)' section.

Back to top

"My BT" lets you manage your account with us, including getting your bills online. When you create a "My BT" account on bt.com, we ask you for information so we can check your identity when you sign in and also if you need help to re-set your password. We may also use some of your account information to tell you about products or services we think you might be interested in – unless you tell us not to.  
Read more about your choices on marketing.

We collect information about how you use our website to keep improving the way it works. We count how many people visit our websites, where they come from, when they visit, how long they stay and what pages they look at. We may associate your device with your account if you log into BT.com. We sometimes use data like this to give us insights into products and services our customers might like and how our advertising performs. We also look at the browser, OS and devices you use to make sure you get a good online experience however you access our websites.

Depending on how you set up your marketing preferences, we may share information about how you've used our website with our advertisers and other companies who offer their services on our pages. We may also use this information to personalise the editorial content and any bt.com service messages based on what you tell us to make sure the online adverts you get are relevant to you.

BT.com cookies collect information about your usage of BT.com including some anonymised account information which you have already given us, such as your age range. We may use cookies to show you relevant adverts based upon this information. This is called Interest-Based Advertising, and you can find out more on our [Advertising Information and Help page](http://bt.custhelp.com/app/answers/detail/a_id/48645/~/in-the-bt-id-sign-up,-what-do-the-online-marketing-preferences-mean%3F) You can [change your cookie preferences](http://home.bt.com/pages/navigation/index.html?page=BTCOM#yourCookieSettings) or read more about our cookie policy – anytime.

Depending on how you have set your cookies preferences we may also allow Interest Based Advertising partners or content providers to collect information about your browsing behaviour in real time and combine it with information about your browsing behaviour on other sites you may visit to show you adverts and content which are relevant to your interests. We may also share information about your browsing behaviour with other service providers to better understand your usage of BT.com services and provide links to related social media content and advertising which may be of interest to you. You can find out more about our service providers, including our Interest Based Advertising and content partners, or opt-out entirely, here.

BT is a participant in the Amazon EU Associates Programme, an affiliate advertising programme designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising and linking to Amazon.co.uk. BT is also a participant in other similar affiliate programmes which means we may be paid commission on sales of those products or services we write about.

Back to top Learn more about cookies

BT may share information about your browsing behaviour with the following companies, in order to provide services which are designed to enhance your experience of BT.com and show you content, social media and advertising which we think may be of interest to you.

If you wish to opt out of all of these services, you can change your cookie preferences for BT.com. Alternatively, to opt out of individual services, you can follow the link to the specific company's privacy policy.

Partner / provider| Service| Privacy Policy  
---|---|---  
Amazon| Interest based advertising.| amazon.com/advertisingpolicy  
amazon.com/privacy  
Audience Science| Interest based advertising.| audiencescience.com/privacy  
Google Analytics| Analysis of website usage.| support.google.com/analytics  
Iris| Interest based content services.| qubit.com/legal/privacy-and-cookie-policy  
Skimlinks| Advertising hyperlinks.| skimlinks.com/privacy-policy  
Social Chorus| Social media services.| socialchorus.com/privacy-policy/  
Yahoo DNS| Search engine services.| policies.yahoo.com/us/en/yahoo/privacy  

### Monitoring Products

When you buy a BT monitoring product from us we ask for your name, title, address, date of birth and gender. We also ask for contact details including a phone number, email address and your current mobile number. We use your personal information to get in touch with you and also to check your identity if you contact us.

To enable us to set up a user account we ask for your username and password and as well as that we ask for details on how you want to pay for any subscriptions or charges, like your bank details or credit card number. (So you can be charged for the service.)

Unless you tell us not to, we will use any of the information that you give us to tell you about products and services we think you might be interested in. We might do that by post, online, using push notifications via apps, or on the phone. Read more about your choices on marketing.

As well as information you give to us when you use your BT monitoring product we record certain things about that use, your IP address, location information (current and historic), video images, pictures, motion detection and timings , which are used to provide the specialist services to you.

Some health products may also collect information such as your height, weight, blood pressure and activity levels so that you can monitor your wellbeing, for example through an app on your phone. Such information will be stored and processed by third parties separately from personal data held about you by other BT suppliers. BT may analyse this data to identify trends in the use of this product or improved the service, but only in aggregated and anonymised form.

Our monitoring products may also gather limited information from your mobile phone in order to provide the service; this may include access to your mobile device type, mobile device ID, and date and time stamps of app use. You can see the permissions we use when downloading the app from your app store

BTs monitoring devices are not currently shown on your "My BT" account on bt.com so you need to change your monitor app or website settings or preferences.

When you use one of BT's monitoring services you may choose to view, access or manage your service through a web page. We do this using 'cookies'. For more information on how BT uses cookies please see the Cookies page, but **please note** that our monitoring pages don't currently use the cookie categories used by the rest of BT, however you can still disable them via your browser.

We don't share your personal information, except with the third parties we work with to deliver your monitoring services. Third parties are often used for notification services, mapping services and specialist consultancy or analysis type services. If you are presented with any additional privacy policies or associated End User License Agreements whilst using BTs monitoring products, we advise you to read those documents carefully.

 **Important  
It is a legal requirement to get the explicit permission of any other individual (or their legal parent or guardian) before you obtain or use any of their personal information collected and provided to you by a BT monitoring product.**

### BT Home Hubs

If you are BT Infinity or BT broadband customer, you will be provided with a BT Home Hub so that you connect your devices to the internet. Your BT Home Hub generates your IP address, which will be refreshed every 28 dates, or when you disconnect it.

These BT Home Hubs will identify and record your device's unique identifier, or "MAC address", and any personalised name you might have given your device. This information – along with the password – allows the Hub to know which devices it should and should not connect with. The MAC address will also provide basic details about your device, such as its manufacturer, and in some cases the specific model of device. BT may use this information to understand when and for how long you use the internet, so BT can manage its network resources better. This information may also help BT identify and resolve any connectivity issues your BT Home Hub and your devices.

BT may also use this information to tell you about products and services we think you might be interested in. We might do that by post, online, using push notifications via apps, text message, or on the phone. Read more about your choices on marketing.

Back to top

### Credit Checks, Fraud Prevention and Debt Recovery

When you order or buy something from us, we might have to do a credit check. That means looking into your records with credit reference agencies (like Experian or Equifax), the Interactive Media in Retail Group (IMRG) security alert, or fraud prevention agencies. When they get a search from us, a 'footprint' goes on your file which other organisations might see.

We might keep personal information we find out about you – but we have a strict policy for how we look after it and keep it safe. We also keep the results of the searches we do with credit agencies so we don't have to do another search if you buy something new from us in the future. But we only keep your credit data for a reasonable amount of time.

We'll also do checks to confirm your identity when you want a new phone line. That's to help protect you from identity theft and fraud, and to prevent and detect crime or money laundering. And once in a while we might run more checks with CRAs and fraud prevention agencies (FPAs) to keep your account with us up to date.

If false or inaccurate information is provided and identified as fraud, the details will be passed to FPAs such as Cifas. This information may also be shared with law enforcement agencies.

We may also share the information with other organisations. This information may be used to prevent fraud and money laundering, for example, when:

  * Checking applications for credit and credit related and other facilities.
  * Managing credit and credit related accounts or facilities.
  * Recovering debt.
  * Checking insurance proposals and claims
  * Checking job applications and employees.

If you tell us you've got a spouse or financial associate, we'll link your records together – so you must make sure you have their agreement to disclose information about them. CRAs also link your records together and these links will stay on your and their files – unless you or your partner successfully files for a disassociation with the CRAs to sever that link.

We send CRAs information on applications, and they hold onto that. We may also give them details of your accounts and bills, including how you manage them. That includes telling them about your account balances, what you pay us and when you miss a payment (going back in the past, too). If you don't pay your bills on time, CRAs will record that. They, or a fraud prevention agency, might tell others doing similar checks – including organisations trying to trace you or recover money you owe them.

There are a few different CRAs in the UK, and each one might have different information on you. If you want to find out what information they have on you, they'll charge you a small statutory fee.

  * Callcredit, Consumer Services Team, PO Box 491, Leeds, LS3 1WZ or 0870 0601414 or [callcredit.co.uk](http://callcredit.co.uk/).
  * Equifax, Credit File Advice Centre, PO Box1140, Bradford, BD1 5US or 0844 3350550 or [equifax.co.uk](http://www.equifax.co.uk/).
  * Experian, Consumer Help Service, PO Box 8000, Nottingham NG80 7WF or 0844 4818000 or [experian.co.uk](http://experian.co.uk/).

If you continue to not pay your bills we may sell the unpaid debt to debt recovery agencies, such as the Lowell Group ([lowellgroup.co.uk/privacy-policy](http://www.lowellgroup.co.uk/index.php/privacy-policy/)). To enable the agency to recover the debt, we will provide them with information about you (such as your name, address and contact information) and your account (such as the amount of the debt).

If you want to receive details of the relevant FPAs, please write to us at:

British Telecommunications plc  
pp 5TH FLOOR  
Londonderry Telephone Exchange  
2 Queens Quay  
Londonderry  
BT48 7AY  

### Disclosure and sharing data

We may share your personal information with other companies in the BT Group, including EE, who may use it for the purposes set out in this Privacy Centre.

We sometimes use other companies to provide some of our services or to provide services to us. To do that, they may need to process your personal information. When we do, they have to follow our instructions and comply with the Data Protection Act 1998.

We might transfer your personal information to places outside the European Economic Area and store it there, where our (or our suppliers') people might process it. If that happens, we require them to apply the same security standards as when we process your information in the UK. Along with other organisations, we and other organisations may access and use the information recorded by the FPAs in other countries outside the UK.

Sometimes we ask specialist partners to call you, on our behalf, to offer you things from BT we think you might want. We've listed these partners [here](http://www.bt.com/partners). If someone contacts you who isn't on the list but claims to be acting for us, get in touch straight away on 0800 800 150 so we can check it out.

BT sometimes receives information requests from law enforcement agencies about its customers for the purposes of preventing and detecting crime, prosecuting offenders, and protecting national security. BT complies with those requests that are lawful.

We also provide information when the law says we have to such as in response to a court order.

### Monitoring and Recording communications

We may monitor and record our communications with you, including e-mails and phone conversations. Information which we collect may then be used for training purposes, quality assurance, to record details about the products and services you order from us or ask us about, and in order to meet our legal and regulatory obligations generally.

We regularly review our privacy policy. The last update was on 22 June 2016.

### Accessing your information

We want to make sure that any data we hold on you is up to date. So if you think your personal information is inaccurate, you can ask us to correct or remove it.

Under the Data Protection Act 1998 individuals have the right to know what information we hold on them. If you'd like a copy of some or all of your personal information, write to us at:

BT PLC  
Crawley TEC, Zone DSAR  
Fleming Way,  
Crawley  
West Sussex,  
RH10 9JY

We charge £10 for requests for personal information – so please enclose a cheque made out to BT with your request.

If you'd like any copies of your phone bills, call 150. There'll be a fee to cover the cost.

Back to top

Unless you tell us not to, we will tell you about BT products and services we think you might be interested in. We might do this through the post, emails, text message, online, using push notifications via apps, or on the phone. We may share your data with third data parties so we can make these messages more relevant to your interests.

We won't send you marketing messages if you tell us not to but we will still need to send you service-related messages. You can opt out of getting marketing messages anytime. You can tell us in lots of ways:

  * When we call you as part of a telemarketing campaign, you can tell us if you don't want to receive any more marketing calls.
  * When we email you, you can use the link in it to opt out of marketing emails.
  * When we text you, you can text back to tell us to stop further SMS marketing.
  * Change the cookie settings we hold for you on BT.com so you don't receive targeted advertising online.

If you want to opt out of postal marketing, or marketing messages all together, you can call us on 0800 800 150.

The ecomm.bt.com domain is managed and administered at BT Walsall, West Midlands, WS1 2HE.

Back to top
